The military swarmed into this city, which had lost its priest and had fallen into disorder,
and attacked the citizens here,
trying to gain control militarily.
You were the one who created the opportunity for them to do that, were you not?
The people of Liore are ethnically very similar to Ishbal.
The folks at Central
must not have thought of them as being the same kind of people as themselves.
That is not true!
I am going to complete
the Philosopher's Stone
for the sake of all people
who suffer under tyranny.
Wait...
Wait!
This one is on a whole other level
compared with the ones Tucker was creating.
Is this the legacy of
the 5th Laboratory?
All of these things were known to you
and Colonel Archer, weren't they, Major?
What the hell are you guys hiding?
We've had enough already.
Please stop!
Al-kun...
Major Armstrong doesn't have anything to do with this.
I'm the one who was
harboring Martel-san.
Wh-What are you talking about,
Alphonse-kun?
There is something that
I've come to understand.
I can't say anything
about it now,
but please, everyone,
no more fighting.
Please, don't fight.
Major, I know that you're trying to carry on where Hughes left off.
"You can just make your way to the top without having to know about anything."
"I will investigate what's happening behind the scenes myself."
Isn't that right?
I'm terribly sorry.
Right now, I'm not...
Al!
Martel-san!
Al, listen to me, and tell Ed, too!
Whatever, just get inside me!
Al, listen...
Martel-san, what on earth is it?
Liore is going to be
turned into another Ishbal!
What do you mean?
That man—the Führer—
is a homunculus!
The military wants to
have a just cause!
That cause being that ultimately, the town of Liore
was the one who first attacked the military,
and thus they had no choice but to massacre us!
Lure the military in
without offering resistance!
When that happens, the wrath of God
will rain down upon them!
It's pretty bad taste to prop up
a mute woman as a holy mother.
Rose-san is the one
who gave us courage!
She's the one who told us
that we can stand under our own power, not by the god Leto, or the military!
It's all the same if it means you're still following somebody else, you know!
What?!
They can't help it.
We humans are so weak, after all.
Lyra, is that perfume?
Yes.
I haven't had
a chance to bathe, you see.
I don't like that smell.
Never mind that,
what are you going to do?
That should be obvious.
You think I can turn a blind eye to what Scar is doing now?
I suppose not.
If this keeps up, there are going to be casualties among the townspeople.
He says he's going to use the inbound military
as ingredients to transmute his Philosopher's Stone.
But if that fails...
And here I thought that
maybe you admired Scar.
We both feel the same way about wanting to protect the city.
Lyra, I need a favor.
Please, I need you to hear me out.
It's Alphonse.
He came from Liore.
He brought a letter
addressed to me.
It's from Brother?
Then he's safe, right?
Yes.
According to Ed-kun's letter,
Scar has turned the whole town into a transmutation circle.
He also says that by no means are we to enter the town.
I wonder if they're planning
to lure the military in and use them as ingredients for the Philosopher's Stone...
How do you mean?
The ingredients for a
Philosopher's Stone are live humans.
And a very large
number of them, at that.
Y-You don't mean...
So that's the truth behind the 5th Laboratory, huh?
Then the higher-ups within the military were sanctioning human experimentation...
Al, you're heading to Liore.
If they're together,
you should meet up with Ed.
Right.
But...
If we leave them alone,
Liore will surrender in time.
Arresting Scar after that happens will be good enough.
Understood.
Al-kun...
This is Ed-kun's.
The Major just returned it to us.
You fools, who defy the military,
away with you!
Animals that can talk?
You must be confused!
Chimeras.
It's them, all right.
What's more, they said
there was a man who could
suddenly create explosions with just his touch.
What?
Is something the matter?
Those guys are just a diversion.
The main enemy forces will
definitely be invading afterward.
As planned, we will draw them into the city,
without offering any resistance.
Before that happens, you're going to escape through that passageway.
I am going to go dispose of the enemy, who has come here as a diversion.
You have an obligation to
make sure they get away safely.
Yeah, okay.
Let's go, Rose, Lyra.
You're being a pretty
good loser, huh?
If that letter has arrived, then the military won't be coming in for the time being.
If Scar can't get the ingredients for his Philosopher's Stone,
then nothing is going to happen.
All I can do
is get you away to someplace
where the military can't reach you.
Liore is going to fall under military command.
If you have to blame someone,
blame me.
I can't overturn
the military's decision.
Look at that!
Seven thousand troops total,
all gathered together.
It would be possible for us to crush Liore right now!
Now, hold on.
Table the attack for now.
What?!
According to the letter that Colonel Mustang received,
the Fullmetal Alchemist appears to still be safe.
Liore may be preparing for a dialogue between us.
There is no possibility of that now!
Still, we cannot very well
invade the city without just cause.
Pride,
what do you mean,
delaying the assault?
Do you have some complaint, Lust?
Scar is lying in wait
for the military to invade.
He intends to use those lives to
transmute the Philosopher's Stone.
So why don't you send
the military in right now?
I am under orders
from you-know-who.
I do not know
what is being considered,
but that person's word is absolute.
Lust...
I cannot accept that.
If Scar is going to create a Philosopher's Stone,
then I am going to help him.
Are you sure you don't embrace any wasted feelings for Scar?
We are allowed to live
because of that person.
Do not forget that.
Which is precisely the reason
why we have been seeking the Philosopher's Stone.
I am going to Liore once again.
Get the military moving as soon as you can.
Gluttony?
But... you-know-who said...
Is fleeing all you can do?
The Ishbalans, who had the
same color of skin that you do,
were a bit more
challenging than you are.
Maybe I was expecting too much from them.
After all that we've done, I thought
they would be fighting back by now,
but I guess we haven't killed enough of them.
So, it is you,
Crimson Alchemist.
And you are?
Ah, I remember.
That scar is one of
my best works.
What's with your right arm?
Of all the State Alchemists
whom I kill,
you will be the last!
What?!
Damn!
That right arm... I get it.
It's just like that one time,
when my red stone was taken.
Feed me as many as you like!
I will take that cursed red light...
and transmute it into a
Philosopher's Stone within me!
Why do we have to
leave the city?
Let's fight!
No! This is the will
of the Holy Mother.
Rose, what will you do if Scar-san
does not come, even after we've fled?
Without the Philosopher's Stone,
we cannot fight.
Cut it out, Lyra.
I'll negotiate with the military.
Somehow or other...
I can't put any trust into that.
We all have to split up and run away in all directions right now.
And then, make our appeals from cities all over.
Tell everyone
what happened in Liore,
what happened in Ishbal in the past, and of the tyranny of the military.
It'll just become another story.
Yet another city tried to create a Philosopher's Stone and was destroyed.
Rose, Lyra, you guys
get out of here too!
I've been waiting for you
and the rest of my body.
You're... Sensei's...
It's Wrath.
Call me Wrath!
Rose! You idiot, stay back!
Shut up.
Shut up!
Dammit!
Rose! Get out of here!
You're just being used by Scar!
You don't have to die for him!
Get going!
I know you guys' weakness.
Greed told me.
When you guys come in contact
with the bones or other remains of
the one whose human transmutation
was the subject of an attempt at reanimation,
you become unable to move.
You guys are impostors.
That's why you cower
when faced with the real thing.
In that case,
I don't have a weakness.
I was transmuted with the remains of my own body as ingredients, after I was stillborn.
My real body is
nowhere to be found.
But if it were,
it would be your body!
What?
Go to where
all the others went!
Okay!
Are you sure
you want to do this?
While you're chasing me around,
the military could be on the move.
I am going to at least avenge my brother
for what you did to him.
What foolishness.
This is a fight over vengeance?
Then what is in this for you?
Nothing.
Nothing?
You killed that many of the
Ishbalan people for nothing?!
To put it my own way,
if you alter a person just a little bit,
they become nothing more than a bomb.
Humans aren't all that great.
You, me—we're all just
meaningless things.
We're all hollow.
I might indeed be hollow...
but I am not meaningless.
Like I said, Alphonse Elric,
I am a State Alchemist,
just like your brother is.
You're nothing more
than a murderer.
Scar-san, please stop too.
Where is my brother?
Stand aside, Alphonse Elric!
There has been
enough bloodshed!
Can't you put an end
to this now, Scar-san?
I did it, I did it!
Your arm has been
superbly transmuted!
Can you hear that?
The countdown to your death?
Your arm is slowly combining with
the oxygen in the air, and before long...
Look closely, and see
whether or not I am hollow...
This is what a real person looks like!
Scar-san!
Go to your brother.
I will do what you two could not.
What are red stones
doing in his silver watch?!
I made a promise, didn't I?
That I was going to
blow you up?
Alphonse!
Ah, you feel so good!
You should make for...
a magnificent bomb!
You... You're the Führer's...
Edward...
Why didn't you make me right?
E...d...
Give me back my body.
Give it back!
Shut up...
Stop...
Make that thing shut up.
Shut up... Shut up...
Get up... and walk!
Shut up!
Move... forward!
Ed!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 42: "His Name Is Unknown"
Brother, is this...
Is this a Philosopher's Stone?